Guide to the Stanford University, Task Force on Fraternities and Sororities, Records
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Stanford University, Task Force on Fraternities and Sororities, records
1952-1988
1983-1984
SC0730
Serbein, Oscar N., 1919-
1 Linear feet (2 boxes)
The records include agenda, minutes, memoranda, correspondence, surveys, background materials, and the published report (1988). The majority of the materials date from 1983-1984; earlier records are photocopies of relevant reports, memoranda, clippings, etc.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Provenance
The records were received by the Stanford University Archvies via administrative transfer in 2004.
Information about Access
The collection is open for research; materials must be requested at least 48 hours in advance of intended use.
Biographical/Historical note
Oscar N. Serbein, professor in the Graduate School of Business at Stanford, was chair of the Task Force on Fraternities and Sororities (1983-1984) whose charge was to conduct a thorough review of the University's policies pertaining to fraternities and sororities and to address the question: "To what degree should fraternal organizations at Stanford be encouraged or discouraged?"
Scope and Contents note
The records include agenda, minutes, memoranda, correspondence, surveys, background materials, and the published report (1988). The majority of the materials date from 1983-1984; earlier records are photocopies of relevant reports, memoranda, clippings, etc.
Access Terms
Stanford University. Task Force on Fraternities and Sororities..; Greek letter societies--California--Stanford.
Collection Contents
- Survey of Fraternity and Sorority Presidents, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 1-3)
- Final report, dissensions and notes (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Fraternity Rush: Interfraternity Council (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Fraternity Rush: Past policies (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Fraternity Rush: The Fraternity at Stanford University (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Fraternity Rush: Assorted topics (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Task Force: Agenda (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Task Force: Minutes, 1983-84 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Task Force: Rosters, Visits, Questionnaires (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Task Force: correspondence, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Task Force: background information (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Task Force: correspondence received, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Task Force: minutes, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Task Force: assorted documents and notes (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Summary report, Survey of Fraternity and Sorority Presidents, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Background materials (Box 2, Folder 7-10)
- Report of the Task Force on Fraternities and Sororities January 1988. Part A (Report) (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Report of the Task Force on Fraternities and Sororities January 1988. Part B (Appendices) (Box 2, Folder 12)